> > Jem Young: 我的大学教授，我最喜欢的教授，博士
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: My professor in college,
my favorite professor, Dr.
大卫 - 吉布森来自我的大学
David Gibson, from my university.
他曾经告诉我 90% 的软件工程师
He once told me that 90% of what
you do as a software engineer
正在将事物写入数据库并从数据库中读取内容。
is writing things into a database and
reading things out of a database.
做了很多年的软件工程师
And having been a software engineer for
many years,
我知道 [ LAUGH] 是绝对正确的。
I know that [LAUGH] is absolutely true.
当你仔细想想你的工作是什么的时候
When you think about what your job
really is, it's mostly reading stuff and
把东西从数据库里写出来
writing stuff out of a database.
尤其是在 UI 工程师和网络开发人员的情况下，我们没有给出很多想法
But especially as UI engineers and web
developers, we don't give a lot of thought
这数据是如何被拯救的，在哪里，它应该在哪里生活。
to how that data is getting saved, where
it's going, where it should even live.
所以当我们谈到保存数据时，最简单的是什么，
So when we talk about saving data,
what's the easiest,
最简单的拯救方法吗
simplest way of saving something?
是否在一段时间内持久保存 ?
Persisting it over time?
>> Studt1: 将其写入文件?
&gt;&gt; Student1: Write it to a file?
>> Jem Young: 一个文件， [LAUGH] 。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: A file, [LAUGH] yeah.
文件是在某个位置保存某些数据的最简单方法。
A file is the simplest way of
saving some data somewhere.
使用文件有什么问题 ?
What's the problem with using a file?
我们为什么不能把一切都保存在档案里
Why can't we just save
everything to a file?
>> Student2: 读和写的开销。
&gt;&gt; Student2: There's overhead
on reading and writing.
数据的管理也很困难。
And it's hard to manage the data.
>> Jem Young: 是的，但还有一点，为什么数据很难管理 ?
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yeah, but a bit more,
why is it hard to manage the data?
>> Student3: Cuz 未按您可能需要的方式进行组织。
&gt;&gt; Student3: Cuz it's not organized
the way that you might need it.
>> Jem Young: 是的，我们可以解决这个问题。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yeah,
we could fix that, though.
那是绝对正确的
That's absolutely right.
但我们可以组织数据，以它对我们有意义的方式进行保存。
But we can organize the data and save it
in such a way that it makes sense to us.
出什么事了
What's the problem?
>> Student3: 您可能只需要几页中的一个字。
&gt;&gt; Student3: You might only need
one word out of several pages.
您必须阅读整个文件才能获得该词的访问权。
And you have to read the entire file in
order to get access to that one word.
>> Jem Young: 是的，文件未被优化为在中间读，
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yeah, files are not
optimized to be read in the middle,
从一开始就结束了
in the beginning, and the end.
我们可以但他们不是为了这个而建的
We can, but they're not built for that.
按我们说的速度
And at the speed we're talking about,
我们每天都在谈论数十亿的交易
we're talking about billions
of transactions a day.
我们需要一些最优化的方法来做到这一点。
We need something that's
optimized to do that.
但我想用纯平的纯文本文件来表达最大的问题
But I'd say the biggest problem with
using just a plain, pure-flat file for
保存数据不是便携的
saving data, it's not portable.
它只会在一台服务器上生存
It's only gonna live on one server.
我们说我有十个服务器，我们都是同时写一个文件吗 ?
And let's say I have ten servers, do we
all write to one file at the same time?
这很困难，因为写文件需要写硬盘，
That would be hard, because writing to
a file requires writing to a hard disk,
而硬盘就像是，不像，它是最慢的缓存级别。
and hard disk is like, not like,
it's the slowest level of caching.
如果您认为将数据写入作为持久数据的某种高速缓存，
And if you think of writing data as
some sort of caching as persisting data,
会有你的 CPU 缓存最快的
there's gonna be your CPU cache
that's gonna be the fastest.
你会有你的记忆缓存
You're gonna have your memory cache.
你会有其他的缓存层
You're gonna have other layers of caching.
最慢的是硬盘高速缓存
And the slowest is gonna
be a hard drive cache.
所以从档案里写得很慢
So writing from a file is gonna be slow.
而且，在成千上万的服务器上持续存在这一点，它是不可扩展的。
And also, persisting that across thousands
of servers, it's just not scalable.
因此，我们需要专门为其构建的某种数据平台
So we need some sort of data platform
that is built specifically for
保存数据和信息。
saving data and information.
这就是为什么发明数据库的原因。
That's why the database was invented.
它为我们提供了一种结构化的方式来保存数据，从而使其可读和
It gives us a structured way of saving
data in such a way that it's readable and
所有各方都可写。
writable by all parties.
这才是合理的
And it just makes sense.
当你在说大数据的时候，我们就会说数据太字节了，
When you're talking big data, so
we're talking petabytes of data,
您必须以可查询的方式来构造该数据。
you have to structure that data
in a way that it's queryable.
我们不能把东西保存在一个硬盘里，希望它能有效。
We can't just save things to a hard drive
somewhere, and hopefully, it works.
希望我能对它进行查询。
And hopefully, I can run queries on it.
你得在某种意义上做到这一点
You have to do it in
a way that makes sense.